<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-01-24T15:36:50+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Ewing Group</title><subtitle>Statistical Cancer Genomics</subtitle><entry><title type="html">NEW PREPRINT: Divergent trajectories to structural diversity impact patient survival in high grade serous ovarian cancer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/publications/2024/01/15/NewPreprint.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NEW PREPRINT: Divergent trajectories to structural diversity impact patient survival in high grade serous ovarian cancer" /><published>2024-01-15T13:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-15T13:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/publications/2024/01/15/NewPreprint</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/publications/2024/01/15/NewPreprint.html">&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;/img/Fig1_markerHGSOC.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have posted a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2024.01.12.575376v1&quot;&gt;new preprint&lt;/a&gt; on bioRxiv ‘Divergent trajectories to structural diversity impact patient survival in high grade serous ovarian cancer’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work highlights high grade serous ovarian carcinoma as an exemplar tumour type for studying chromosomal instability and is the result of a combined effort across the Scottish High Grade Serous Ovarian Consortium to comprehensively characterise the mutational landscape driving high grade serous ovarian cancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have highlighted our main findings in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/Ailith_Ewing/status/1747291048206901394?s=20&quot;&gt;tweetorial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well done to &lt;a href=&quot;/Kitty&quot;&gt;Kitty&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/Jo&quot;&gt;Jo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;span style=&quot;color:#0000EE&quot;&gt;Stuart&lt;/span&gt; for all the work they contributed to this study!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt; Abstract &lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deciphering the structural variation across tumour genomes is crucial to determine the
events driving tumour progression and better understand tumour adaptation and evolution.
High grade serous ovarian cancer (HGSOC) is an exemplar tumour type showing extreme,
but poorly characterised structural diversity. We comprehensively describe the mutational
landscape driving HGSOC, exploiting a large (N=324), deeply whole genome sequenced
dataset. We reveal two divergent evolutionary trajectories, affecting patient survival and
involving differing genomic environments. One involves homologous recombination repair
deficiency (HRD) while the other is dominated by whole genome duplication (WGD) with
frequent chromothripsis, breakage-fusion-bridges and extra-chromosomal DNA. These
trajectories contribute to structural variation hotspots, containing novel candidate driver
genes with significantly altered expression. While structural variation predominantly drives
tumorigenesis, we also find high mtDNA mutation loads associated with shorter patient
survival, and acting in combination with alterations in the nuclear genome to impact
prognosis and suggesting new strategies for patient stratification.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ailith</name></author><category term="publications" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Congratulations! Dr Stuart Brown passed his viva!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/launches/2023/12/04/DrSBrown.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Congratulations! Dr Stuart Brown passed his viva!" /><published>2023-12-04T08:27:48+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-04T08:27:48+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/launches/2023/12/04/DrSBrown</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/launches/2023/12/04/DrSBrown.html">&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;/img/SBrown_pokemon.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr Stuart Brown passed his viva with minor corrections!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His thesis titled:
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;center&gt;&apos;Genomic catastrophes: Complex Structural Variants in High Grade Serous Ovarian Cancer&apos;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
investigates the prevalence, co-occurrence, distribution, and impact of multiple complex structural variant types on survival in high grade serous ovarian cancer and provides novel insights into the genomic diversity of high grade serous ovarian cancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stuart is now working as a postdoc in Prof Bass Hassan’s research group at the University of Oxford, applying his skills to study the genomics of sarcoma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations Stuart!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ailith</name></author><category term="launches" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome Rashi and Ismail to the group!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/launches/2023/09/01/WelcomeRashiIsmail.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome Rashi and Ismail to the group!" /><published>2023-09-01T09:27:48+01:00</published><updated>2023-09-01T09:27:48+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/launches/2023/09/01/WelcomeRashiIsmail</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/launches/2023/09/01/WelcomeRashiIsmail.html">&lt;div class=&quot;columns&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;column&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/img/Rashi.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rashi&quot; width=&quot;410&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;column&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/img/Ismail.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ismail&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are delighted to welcome &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/Rashi&quot;&gt;Rashi Krishna&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/Ismail&quot;&gt;İsmail Özkaraca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; to the group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rashi is a PhD student co-supervised with Prof Val Brunton and aims to identify drug response biomarkers in uterine leiomyosarcoma. We are excited to have Rashi in the group as she delves into computational cancer genomics alongside her experimental work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome also to İsmail who joins the group as a postdoctoral fellow interested in the modelling of spatiotemporal trajectories of structural variation in high grade serous ovarian cancers. We’re looking forward to supporting İsmail as he applies his mathematical skills and experience to tumour biology.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ailith</name></author><category term="launches" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Mark Foundation Chromosomal Instability in Cancer workshop</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/launches/2023/06/29/MarkFoundationCIN.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Mark Foundation Chromosomal Instability in Cancer workshop" /><published>2023-06-29T09:27:48+01:00</published><updated>2023-06-29T09:27:48+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/launches/2023/06/29/MarkFoundationCIN</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/launches/2023/06/29/MarkFoundationCIN.html">&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;/img/MarkFoundation.png&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Img credit: The Mark Foundation for Cancer Research&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ailith was pleased to take a week off from changing nappies during her maternity leave to attend the Mark Foundation workshop on chromosomal instability in cancer at Barts Cancer Institute in London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a fantastic meeting full of: big ideas conveyed by flip chart only chalk talks, many useful and interesting discussions, and outstanding kareoke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the organisers Florian Markovetz, Peter van Loo and Sarah McClelland for the invite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch this space for more CINful activity in the future…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ailith</name></author><category term="launches" /><summary type="html">Img credit: The Mark Foundation for Cancer Research</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New paper from Kitty: Germline de novo mutations in families with Mendelian cancer syndromes caused by defects in DNA repair</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/launches/2023/06/20/KittyNatComms.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New paper from Kitty: Germline de novo mutations in families with Mendelian cancer syndromes caused by defects in DNA repair" /><published>2023-06-20T09:27:48+01:00</published><updated>2023-06-20T09:27:48+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/launches/2023/06/20/KittyNatComms</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/launches/2023/06/20/KittyNatComms.html">&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img width=&quot;450&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; src=&quot;/img/KittyPaper.png&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-023-39248-0&quot;&gt;Sherwood et al (2023) Nat. Comms Fig 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kitty’s paper &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-023-39248-0&quot;&gt;‘Germline de novo mutations in families with Mendelian cancer syndromes caused by defects in DNA repair’&lt;/a&gt; is now out in Nature Communications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DNA repair defects underlie many cancer syndromes. We tested whether de novo germline mutations (DNMs) are increased in families with germline defects in polymerase proofreading or base excision repair. A parent with a single germline POLE or POLD1 mutation, or biallelic MUTYH mutations, had 3-4 fold increased DNMs over sex-matched controls. POLE had the largest effect. The DNMs carried mutational signatures of the appropriate DNA repair deficiency. No DNM increase occurred in offspring of MUTYH heterozygous parents. Parental DNA repair defects caused about 20–150 DNMs per child, additional to the ~60 found in controls, but almost all extra DNMs occurred in non-coding regions. No increase in post-zygotic mutations was detected, excepting a child with bi-allelic MUTYH mutations who was excluded from the main analysis; she had received chemotherapy and may have undergone oligoclonal haematopoiesis. Inherited DNA repair defects associated with base pair-level mutations increase DNMs, but phenotypic consequences appear unlikely.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;columns&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/img/Kitty.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kitty&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;column is-8&quot;&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;From Kitty:&lt;/p&gt;
            
                 &lt;p&gt;&apos;Really excited to share our paper out today! We show how germline de novo mutation rates and signatures are associated with parental germline mutation status in POLE, POLD1 and MUTYH.&lt;/p&gt;
            
                 &lt;p&gt;   Huge thanks to everyone involved!&apos; &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Well done Kitty!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ailith</name></author><category term="launches" /><summary type="html">Source: Sherwood et al (2023) Nat. Comms Fig 1</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Funding success: Ailith wins IGC Langmuir Talent Development Fellowship in Cancer Research</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/launches/2022/09/05/IGCLangmuirAward.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Funding success: Ailith wins IGC Langmuir Talent Development Fellowship in Cancer Research" /><published>2022-09-05T09:27:48+01:00</published><updated>2022-09-05T09:27:48+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/launches/2022/09/05/IGCLangmuirAward</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/launches/2022/09/05/IGCLangmuirAward.html">&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; src=&quot;/img/IGCLangmuir.png&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ed.ac.uk/institute-genetics-cancer/news-and-events/news-2022/igc-langmuir-talent-dev-fellowship-cancer-research&quot;&gt;IGC webpages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m delighted to have been awarded an inaugural IGC Langmuir Talent Development fellowship and am immensely grateful to Hugh and Josseline Langmuir for the generous philanthropic donation that made these awards possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an excellent opportunity at a tricky point in my research career and will hugely benefit my career progression. As a recently appointed cross-disciplinary Chancellor’s Fellow at the Institute of Genetics and Cancer, I am in the process of starting my own research group to develop and apply statistical and computational approaches to analyse large cancer datasets to learn about tumour biology and explore ways of translating our discoveries into the clinic through collaboration with our clinical partners in the CRUK Scotland Centre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This award will act as a springboard allowing us the financial breathing space to generate the vital preliminary data necessary to demonstrate in future funding applications the merits and feasibility of this line of research. It will provide the resources to allow us to focus on putting our ideas into practice which I expect in the course of the fellowship will reveal exciting insights into tumour biology and help establish the research identity of our group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations also to the other recipients of these inaugural fellowships: my talented colleagues Dr Ava Khamseh and Dr Robb Hollis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Link to full IGC press release: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ed.ac.uk/institute-genetics-cancer/news-and-events/news-2022/igc-langmuir-talent-dev-fellowship-cancer-research&quot;&gt;https://www.ed.ac.uk/institute-genetics-cancer/news-and-events/news-2022/igc-langmuir-talent-dev-fellowship-cancer-research&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ailith</name></author><category term="launches" /><summary type="html">Source: IGC webpages</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">WE ARE HIRING! - CLOSED</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/launches/2022/05/10/WEAREHIRING.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WE ARE HIRING! - CLOSED" /><published>2022-05-10T09:27:48+01:00</published><updated>2022-05-10T09:27:48+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/launches/2022/05/10/WEAREHIRING</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/launches/2022/05/10/WEAREHIRING.html">&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; src=&quot;/img/CraigIGCview.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;View from IGC over Edinburgh. Photo credit Craig Nicol, IGC graphics&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Are you excited to develop and apply statistical and computational methods to disentangle the structural variant landscape in tumours?&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are looking for an enthusiastic and highly motivated quantitative scientist, interested in applying their expertise to studying cancer genomics and evolution using cutting edge, data-driven approaches. The overall goal is to model the spatiotemporal evolutionary trajectories of structural variants in tumours to inform patient stratification, better predict treatment response and improve clinical outcome for patients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an excellent opportunity to undertake world-class interdisciplinary science driven by clinically important questions. You will play a critical role in the statistical analyses of large cancer sequencing datasets and will be embedded in a cross-disciplinary team at the Institute of Genetics and Cancer, working collaboratively with clinicians, biologists, and other computational scientists. The position is available for 2 years, with a start date as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This position would suit &lt;b&gt;EITHER&lt;/b&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
A skilled quantitative scientist with a research background in any of maths, statistics, physics, computer science (or related disciplines) &lt;br /&gt;AND who is motivated to learn how to apply their skills to biomedical questions
&lt;br /&gt;
OR
&lt;br /&gt;
A computational biologist with experience analysing high-throughput genomic data, particularly from tumours.
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please drop me an email (Dr Ailith Ewing (Ailith.Ewing@ed.ac.uk)) with any informal enquiries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Closing date 7th June 2022 5pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://elxw.fa.em3.oraclecloud.com/hcmUI/CandidateExperience/en/sites/CX_1001/job/4143&quot; class=&quot;button is-primary&quot;&gt;
Apply here!
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ailith</name></author><category term="launches" /><summary type="html">View from IGC over Edinburgh. Photo credit Craig Nicol, IGC graphics</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Review: The evolutionary and clinical impacts of SVs in tumours</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/launches/2022/04/28/NewReview.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Review: The evolutionary and clinical impacts of SVs in tumours" /><published>2022-04-28T09:27:48+01:00</published><updated>2022-04-28T09:27:48+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/launches/2022/04/28/NewReview</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/launches/2022/04/28/NewReview.html">&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; src=&quot;/img/NewReview.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our invited contribution to the 2022 Annual Review Issue: ‘Recent Advances in Pathology’ is published at the Journal of Pathology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;b&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/path.5901&quot;&gt; Unravelling the tumour genome: The evolutionary and clinical impacts of structural variants in tumourigenesis &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Structural variants (SVs) represent a major source of aberration in tumour genomes. Given the diversity in the size and type of SVs present in tumours, the accurate detection and interpretation of SVs in tumours is challenging. New classes of complex structural events in tumours are discovered frequently, and the definitions of the genomic consequences of complex events are constantly being refined. Detailed analyses of short-read whole-genome sequencing (WGS) data from large tumour cohorts facilitate the interrogation of SVs at orders of magnitude greater scale and depth. However, the inherent technical limitations of short-read WGS prevent us from accurately detecting and investigating the impact of all the SVs present in tumours. The expanded use of long-read WGS will be critical for improving the accuracy of SV detection, and in fully resolving complex SV events, both of which are crucial for determining the impact of SVs on tumour progression and clinical outcome. Despite the present limitations, we demonstrate that SVs play an important role in tumourigenesis. In particular, SVs contribute significantly to late-stage tumour development and to intratumoural heterogeneity. The evolutionary trajectories of SVs represent a window into the clonal dynamics in tumours, a comprehensive understanding of which will be vital for influencing patient outcomes in the future. Recent findings have highlighted many clinical applications of SVs in cancer, from early detection to biomarkers for treatment response and prognosis. As the methods to detect and interpret SVs improve, elucidating the full breadth of the complex SV landscape and determining how these events modulate tumour evolution will improve our understanding of cancer biology and our ability to capitalise on the utility of SVs in the clinical management of cancer patients.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ailith</name></author><category term="launches" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome Jo Mattocks to the group!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/launches/2022/04/01/WelcomeJo.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome Jo Mattocks to the group!" /><published>2022-04-01T09:27:48+01:00</published><updated>2022-04-01T09:27:48+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/launches/2022/04/01/WelcomeJo</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/launches/2022/04/01/WelcomeJo.html">&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img width=&quot;230&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;/img/JoHeadshot.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are delighted to welcome &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/Jo&quot;&gt;Jo Mattocks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; to the group for the duration of her PhD studies. Jo is part of the highly-competitive MRC Human Genetics Unit 4-year PhD programme and we are excited to support Jo in her studies over the next few years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jo is interested in the modelling of spatiotemporal trajectories of mutation in high grade serous ovarian cancers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are currently expanding the group so please keep an eye out for &lt;b&gt;post-doc ads coming very soon&lt;/b&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img width=&quot;460&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;/img/Inclusive.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ailith</name></author><category term="launches" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">GOG281/LOGS clinical trial released in The Lancet</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/launches/2022/02/04/LOGStrial.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GOG281/LOGS clinical trial released in The Lancet" /><published>2022-02-04T08:27:48+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-04T08:27:48+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/launches/2022/02/04/LOGStrial</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/launches/2022/02/04/LOGStrial.html">&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img width=&quot;460&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;/img/LOGSPieChart.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thelancet.com/journals/lancet/article/PIIS0140-6736(21)02175-9/fulltext&quot;&gt;GOG281/LOGS clinical trial&lt;/a&gt; was released today in The Lancet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trial demonstrated, for the first time, a new standard of care option for women with progressive or relapsed low-grade serous ovarian cancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trametinib, currently used to treat skin and lung cancers, was found to slow the progression of low-grade serous ovarian cancer and increase the number of patients who respond to treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were pleased to contribute to the molecular characterisation of these tumours by processing the sequencing data from their exomes, a small contribution to a much larger team effort led by researchers at the University of Edinburgh and the University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ailith</name></author><category term="launches" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>