<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-07-05T11:40:38+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Ewing Group</title><subtitle>Statistical Cancer Genomics</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Structural variants at BRCA1/2 and homologous repair deficiency: published in Clinical Cancer Research</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/publications/2021/06/01/BRCA-SVs-published.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Structural variants at BRCA1/2 and homologous repair deficiency: published in Clinical Cancer Research" /><published>2021-06-01T22:27:48+01:00</published><updated>2021-06-01T22:27:48+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/publications/2021/06/01/BRCA-SVs-published</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/publications/2021/06/01/BRCA-SVs-published.html">&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://clincancerres.aacrjournals.org/content/27/11/3201&quot;&gt;recent work&lt;/a&gt; ‘Structural Variants at the &lt;em&gt;BRCA1/2&lt;/em&gt; Loci are a Common Source of Homologous Repair Deficiency in High-grade Serous Ovarian Carcinoma’ is published in Clinical Cancer Research. Clin Cancer Res June 1 2021 (27) (11) 3201-3214; DOI: 10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-20-4068.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first time, we have found large deletions at the &lt;em&gt;BRCA1/2&lt;/em&gt; genes that reduce the activity of these genes in ovarian and other cancers. These deletions contribute to a reduction in the tumour’s ability to repair its DNA accurately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tumours that cannot repair their DNA in this way can be treated very effectively with PARP inhibitors. The detection of these deletions in patient’s tumours could identify more patients that may benefit from this effective therapy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work is the first output from a great collaboration with Prof Charlie Gourley in the CRUK Edinburgh Centre, together with academic, clinical and industry partners, to generate WGS data for high grade serous ovarian tumour samples. I have also written about it in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Ailith_Ewing/status/1260484552172199936&quot;&gt;tweetorial&lt;/a&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/BRCASVs.png&quot; alt=&quot;BRCASVs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ailith</name></author><category term="publications" /><summary type="html">Our recent work ‘Structural Variants at the BRCA1/2 Loci are a Common Source of Homologous Repair Deficiency in High-grade Serous Ovarian Carcinoma’ is published in Clinical Cancer Research. Clin Cancer Res June 1 2021 (27) (11) 3201-3214; DOI: 10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-20-4068.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Ewing Group opened today!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/launches/2021/04/01/ewing-lab-opens.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Ewing Group opened today!" /><published>2021-04-01T22:27:48+01:00</published><updated>2021-04-01T22:27:48+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/launches/2021/04/01/ewing-lab-opens</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/launches/2021/04/01/ewing-lab-opens.html">&lt;p&gt;We are jointly based at the MRC Human Genetics Unit and the Cancer Research UK Edinburgh Centre in the Institute of Genetics and Cancer at the University of Edinburgh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We use statistical genomics to understand how patterns of structural variants (SVs) evolve during tumourigenesis. Genome-wide patterns of SVs in tumours are a consequence of processes of mutation and repair fluctuating throughout tumour evolution. Although single nucleotide variant (SNV) patterns are well established, our understanding of the analogous patterns seen for SVs is rudimentary. Describing the dynamics of these complex patterns parsimoniously is statistically challenging and increasing volumes of whole genome sequencing (WGS) data from tumours have revealed ever more complex classes of SVs. Yet, a full account of tumour evolution depends upon the true prevalence, temporal dynamics and functional impact of these events. Meanwhile, the clinical impact of these events is poorly understood and likely to be underappreciated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We aim to bridge the gap between germline variation and somatic structural variation observed in highly rearranged cancer types, using statistical genomics to identify novel classes of evolutionary biomarkers. Such biomarkers describe how genome-wide patterns of SVs evolve during tumourigenesis. With the increasing availability of longitudinal and multi-region sampling over tumour evolution, evolutionary biomarkers represent a new frontier in translational cancer genomics. Our research benefits from existing and newly established collaborations with world-leading cancer researchers in ovarian and colorectal cancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;columns&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;column&quot;&gt;
                &lt;img src=&quot;/img/MRC_HGU.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;MRC HGU logo&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;column&quot;&gt;
                &lt;img src=&quot;/img/CRUK.png&quot; alt=&quot;CRUK&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Ailith</name></author><category term="launches" /><summary type="html">We are jointly based at the MRC Human Genetics Unit and the Cancer Research UK Edinburgh Centre in the Institute of Genetics and Cancer at the University of Edinburgh.</summary></entry></feed>